<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Kirk Andersen</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://kirkandersen.net/atom.xml" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012-02-28://12</id>
    <updated>2012-04-24T10:37:36Z</updated>
    <subtitle>We&apos;d be no poorer if desuetude, for one, fell into a state of itself. -- Cecil Adams, The Straight Dope</subtitle>
    <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Pro 4.38</generator>

<entry>
    <title>Back with another of those pop lockin&apos; beats...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/back-with-another-of-those-pop-lockin-beats.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.538</id>

    <published>2012-04-24T10:32:58Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-24T10:37:36Z</updated>

    <summary>Ooh, how I wish I had moves like this. In a lot of ways it seems more like &quot;rapping mime&quot; than anything else, but I&apos;ve always loved dance moves that combine fluidity and sharp movements. The first girl in particular...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="music" label="music" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="poplocking" label="pop locking" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="rap" label="rap" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[Ooh, how I wish I had moves like this. In a lot of ways it seems more like "rapping mime" than anything else, but I've always loved dance moves that combine fluidity and sharp movements. The first girl in particular is out of sight, but check out the guy (Salah, I think his name is) from minute 4:07. Great stuff. The background song is pretty cool as well -- anything with thumping bass.

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/GWKDlF_oAXI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>ChronoZoom Project</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/chronozoom-project.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.537</id>

    <published>2012-04-13T12:41:53Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-13T12:46:42Z</updated>

    <summary>Another fun little way to see just how insignificant (yet special! And doubtlessly to the right species, tasty!) we are in the cosmos, check out the time line of the universe here courtesy of the ChronoZoom Project. It&apos;s fascinating to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="cosmology" label="cosmology" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="physics" label="physics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="science" label="Science" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="universe" label="universe" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[Another fun little way to see just how insignificant (yet special! And doubtlessly to the right species, tasty!) we are in the cosmos, check out the <a href="mailto:http://www.chronozoomproject.org/#/t55@x=0&amp;y=0&amp;w=1.1272233750014657&amp;h=1.0560224089635857">time line of the universe here courtesy of the ChronoZoom Project</a>. It's fascinating to look at the whole block of known time, and then to zoom in on just how everything human is just the tiniest little blip. <br /><br />Again though, some of us, really tasty. Please though, hold the ketchup.<br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Horseback archery competition (流鏑馬) in Kyoto on May 3</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/horseback-archery-competition-in-kyoto-on-may-3.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.536</id>

    <published>2012-04-13T05:17:55Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-13T05:50:19Z</updated>

    <summary>If you&apos;re in Kyoto for Golden Week, or just happen to be in Kyoto in general around May 3, be sure to stop by Shimogamo Shrine (下鴨神社) for the annual horseback archery competition (流鏑馬（やぶさめ））. (Japanese) You can find an English...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="horsebackarchery" label="horseback archery" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="kyoto" label="Kyoto" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="kyotosightseeing" label="Kyoto sightseeing" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="yabusame" label="Yabusame" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[If you're in Kyoto for Golden Week, or just happen to be in Kyoto in general around May 3, be sure to stop by Shimogamo Shrine (下鴨神社) for the <a href="http://www.kyotokk.com/yabusame.html">annual horseback archery competition (流鏑馬（やぶさめ））</a>. (Japanese) You can find an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yabusame">English site describing the event here</a>. <br /><br />The event starts at 13:00, but based on personal experience you'll want to get there as early as you can to get a good spot. I've gone as early as 11:00 or so and it was already crowded. The event is free, although there is paid (and better) seating at the front. (What ancient spirit you have to defeat in thumb wrestling to qualify for a paid spot, I cannot say...) Standing atop of step ladders (on going piggy back) is frowned upon, if not outright prohibited.<br /><br />The horses need some time to "rev up," so I suggest sitting toward the middle or end to really see them in action. It's an event of religious significance (the lead up to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aoi_Matsuri">Aoi Matsuri</a>), so having the best rider first to hit all the targets is important. I usually watch the first 5 - 10 passes and call it a day; the riders aren't going to be getting any better, and it's not like later riders are switching to Gatling guns or wearing flaming sombreros. <br /><br />It's pretty cool to see them in action though, flaming sombreros or not. Shimogamo Shrine is usually beautiful that time of year too, and it's a pretty impressive (and expansive) place, so come early to walk around, or go exploring when the rest of the rubes are waiting for the flaming hats.<br /><br />Your best bet if coming from Osaka/Kobe is to take the Keihan Line to its terminus, Demachiyanagi Station (出町柳駅）. It's a short walk from there. There's also the Kyoto Karasuma subway line (烏丸線） -- you'll want to get off at Imadegawa and take a bus from there for Demachiyanagi. Just look around for a bus stop along Imadegawa (in front of Doshisha University would be best/easiest). Buses in that direction come fairly frequently (220 yen). You can also take a cab from Imadegawa to Demachiyanagi for maybe 800 yen or so. Not too bad. The <a href="www.pref.kyoto.jp/visitkyoto/en/theme/sites/shrines/w_heritage/02/">English website for the shrine</a> sez to take a city bus, but remember the first Golden Rule of Kyoto: Never, ever, ever take a bus from Kyoto Station. Too much traffic; you'll never get to where you're going.<br /><br />Enjoy! Incidentally, skip Aoi Matsuri. Ain't worth it.<br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Eudemonia</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/eudemonia.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.535</id>

    <published>2012-04-13T05:13:26Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-13T05:15:59Z</updated>

    <summary>I can think of no better way to live...Well, that and having electrified nunchucks for hands......</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="english" label="English" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="language" label="language" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="linguistics" label="linguistics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[<a href="http://dictionary.reference.com/wordoftheday/archive/2012/03/29.html">I can think of no better way to live</a>...<br /><br />Well, that and having electrified nunchucks for hands...<br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Google Maps on Nintendo and other bits of game nostalgia</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/google-maps-on-nintendo-and-other-bits-of-game-nostalgia.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.534</id>

    <published>2012-04-13T00:24:18Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-13T00:38:14Z</updated>

    <summary>Heh, would be kinda cool. Too bad it&apos;s an April Fool&apos;s joke by Google Maps/Earth. Man, as nostalgic as some of those Nintendo games were, I&apos;m glad games have advanced beyond that. Still, it&apos;d be nice to have a Nintendo...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="games" label="games" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[Heh, <a href="http://google-latlong.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/begin-your-quest-with-google-maps-8-bit.html">would be kinda cool</a>. Too bad it's an April Fool's joke by Google Maps/Earth. Man, as nostalgic as some of those Nintendo games were, I'm glad games have advanced beyond that. Still, it'd be nice to have a Nintendo just as an <a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/96827992/nintendo-controller-coffee-table?image_id=326464209">excuse to buy this controller</a>. <br /><br />I miss old arcade games as well. Now that I'm (technically) an adult, I have the money to blow in a vain attempt to relive the glory days while shutting out the remaining 90% of bile, such as by buying an actual arcade game of my own! <a href="http://www.bmigaming.com/games-video-classicarcadegames.htm">BMI Gaming offers stand up arcade games</a> crammed with all your favorites from the Golden Era of arcade games! They even ship to Japan! Man, I remember playing the HELL out of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Tiger_%28video_game%29">Black Tiger</a>, but I think my all time favorite, and the one I would so desperately <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crossbow_%28video_game%29">love to own, is Crossbow</a>. Man, that game more than any game inspired my love of video games and fantasy. Sigh... Chuck E. Cheese was never the same when they got rid of that game. <br /><br />And...cue Cat's In The Cradle!<br /><br /><br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The Scale of the Universe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/the-scale-of-the-universe.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.533</id>

    <published>2012-04-13T00:17:17Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-13T00:22:36Z</updated>

    <summary>Ever wonder what&apos;s bigger: A grain of sand, or an LCD pixel? Or just wanted help visualizing how big an AM radio wave is? Then check out the Scale of the Universe 2 here! Created by Cary and Michael Huang,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="physics" label="physics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="science" label="science" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="universe" label="universe" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[Ever wonder what's bigger: A grain of sand, or an LCD pixel? Or just wanted help visualizing how big an AM radio wave is? Then check out the <a href="http://htwins.net/scale2/">Scale of the Universe 2 here</a>! Created by Cary and Michael Huang, it's a fascinating way to learn more about the world and the universe around us, and the descriptions (when you click on something) are often pretty hilarious. They also have some more fun games and quizzes on their site, so have fun! ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>SWTOR</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/swtor.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.532</id>

    <published>2012-04-03T12:30:38Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-03T13:02:58Z</updated>

    <summary>Drawn in...can&apos;t help... C&apos;mon! I mean, who hasn&apos;t wanted to be a Jedi? Although, I am rolling as an Imperial Sniper right now. Even though it&apos;s an MMORPG, it&apos;s still sparsely populated enough to qualify as a massively awesome single...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="games" label="games" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="mmorpg" label="MMORPG" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="swtor" label="SWTOR" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[<a href="http://www.swtor.com/">Drawn in...can't help...</a>

C'mon! I mean, who hasn't wanted to be a Jedi? Although, I am rolling as an Imperial Sniper right now. Even though it's an MMORPG, it's still sparsely populated enough to qualify as a massively awesome single player game.

And seriously, watch the cinematics and CREAM YOUR JEANS wishing this was part of a movie. ("Cream Your Jeans" trademark of Kentucky Fried Movie, this website not responsible for regrettable pubescent memories that phrase may evoke.)

The 2nd and 3rd parts are the best. Just sayin'.

<iframe width="470" height="269" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/x2eNr9Oyttk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Japan March 11, 2011 earthquake made easy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/japan-march-11-2011-earthquake-made-easy.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.531</id>

    <published>2012-04-03T12:03:15Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-03T12:14:08Z</updated>

    <summary>The following video is an extraordinarily easy to understand representation of just how powerful the March 11, 2011 earthquake to strike off the Tohoku Region of Japan was. Seriously, not to deprecate the Chile earthquake of 2010, or the huge...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[The following video is an extraordinarily easy to understand representation of just how powerful the March 11, 2011 earthquake to strike off the Tohoku Region of Japan was. Seriously, not to deprecate the Chile earthquake of 2010, or the huge tsunami and earthquake to hit Indonesia in 2004. But this video shows just how hard an earthquake of that size hits ANYWHERE, not just Japan.

For best effect, put on some headphones, and crank the bass wayyyyyy up...

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/eKp5cA2sM28" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


For a more global view, check it out here.

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/cwWn_W6ZbT4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>How the moon was formed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/how-the-moon-was-formed.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.530</id>

    <published>2012-04-03T11:45:10Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-03T11:55:27Z</updated>

    <summary>The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter has shed some new light on the origins of the moon, made extraordinarily easy to understand and fun by NASA. Check it out below. There&apos;s still some conjecture out there, but that&apos;s the fun of science,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="astronomy" label="astronomy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="physics" label="physics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="science" label="Science" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[The <a href="http://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/LRO/main/index.html">Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter</a> has shed some new light on the origins of the moon, made extraordinarily easy to understand and fun by NASA. Check it out below. There's still some conjecture out there, but that's the fun of science, right? To solve the mysteries of the unknown.


<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/TuHasBN-U1c" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Never...I mean ALWAYS...trust a Kiwi</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/neveri-mean-alwaystrust-a-kiwi.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.529</id>

    <published>2012-04-03T11:36:54Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-03T11:43:44Z</updated>

    <summary>How corrupt is YOUR country? How? HOW MUCH?! TELL ME!!!!!Dunno? Well, check it out at the Corruptions Perception Index 2011. The Kiwis come in at No. 1, meaning the least corrupt on the planet. No surprise, really -- stand up...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="america" label="America" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="chicago" label="Chicago" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="politics" label="politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[How corrupt is YOUR country? How? HOW MUCH?! TELL ME!!!!!<br /><br />Dunno? Well, check it out at the <a href="http://cpi.transparency.org/cpi2011/results/">Corruptions Perception Index 2011</a>. <br /><br />The Kiwis come in at No. 1, meaning the least corrupt on the planet. No surprise, really -- stand up folks, each and every one I've ever met. Japan, where I live? 14. Not bad. The US, who I am? 24! Wow! <br /><br />I'm guessing Chicago dragged it down a bit. Sorry, everyone, but it's a small price to pay for being the best city in America with the best pizza, sausages, hot dogs, and smoked fish. Oh, and art museum. Ever been to the Chicago Museum of Art? Them's some good art!<br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Kyoto Imperial Palace open to the public April 4 - 9, 2012</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/kyoto-imperial-palace-open-to-the-public-april-4---9-2012.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.528</id>

    <published>2012-04-03T11:28:58Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-03T11:34:56Z</updated>

    <summary>Those of you out Kyoto way, don&apos;t miss the opening of the Kyoto Imperial Palace to the general public. (京都御所一般公開)The Imperial Gardens themselves (御苑) are extraordinarily beautiful, peaceful, and one of my favorite places in Kyoto. I&apos;ve spent many an...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="kyoto" label="Kyoto" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="tourism" label="tourism" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[Those of you out Kyoto way, don't miss the opening of the Kyoto Imperial Palace to the general public. (京都御所一般公開)<br /><br />The Imperial Gardens themselves (御苑) are extraordinarily beautiful, peaceful, and one of my favorite places in Kyoto. I've spent many an afternoon sitting peacefully under an inviting tree. Normally you need to be part of a tour to enter the Imperial Palace itself, but it's open to the public twice a year, once in Spring and once in fall, and it's not to miss!<br /><br />You'll <a href="http://www.kunaicho.go.jp/event/kyotogosho/kyotogosho.html">find the website here</a>. I found an <a href="http://sankan.kunaicho.go.jp/InfoDetail_KYOTO.html">English version</a> on the ol' Information Superhighway too. <br /><br />I'll try to snap some photos and post 'em later!<br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>DARE, not to be stupid</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/04/dare-not-to-be-stupid.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.527</id>

    <published>2012-04-03T11:24:10Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-03T11:27:39Z</updated>

    <summary>Work has finally been completed on the Dictionary of Regional American English. A five decade long project (!), it is the most thorough dictionary of regional Americanisms to date. You can see a small sample of these regionalisms here. I...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="americanisms" label="Americanisms" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="english" label="English" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="linguistics" label="linguistics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[Work has finally been completed on the <a href="http://dare.news.wisc.edu/">Dictionary of Regional American English</a>. A five decade long project (!), it is the most thorough dictionary of regional Americanisms to date. You can see a small sample of these regionalisms <a href="http://dare.wisc.edu/?q=node/163">here</a>. I only knew 8 of the 100, mostly either the West Coast terms (bear claw) or northern Midwest terms (kitty corner), and a few from forays into cooking (lutefisk). Still, pretty cool. I've always enjoyed finding out that English words that I think are common place are in fact Americanisms -- I remember startling an Australian friend when I asked if I could crack her window a bit (as in to open it slightly)... Any regionalisms you're fond of? To our global readers, any Americanisms you enjoy or are stymied by? 


Oh, okay, FINE! Here! The classic Weird Al Yankovic song "Dare to Be Stupid" too. That's what you clicked this entry to see all along, isn't it?! Sigh...
<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/SMhwddNQSWQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The dos and DO NOT DOs of dontation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/03/the-dos-and-do-not-dos-of-dontation.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.526</id>

    <published>2012-03-16T06:00:13Z</published>
    <updated>2012-03-16T06:36:06Z</updated>

    <summary>Foreign Policy has an interesting article entitled &quot;Haiti Doesn&apos;t Need Your Yoga Mat.&quot; What I found more interesting were the narrow-minded comments of the article. I felt that the main point of the article is that just because it&apos;s charity,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="foreignpolicy" label="Foreign Policy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[Foreign Policy has an interesting article entitled "<a href="http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2011/10/10/stuff_we_dont_want_haiti#0">Haiti Doesn't Need Your Yoga Mat</a>." <br /><br />What I found more interesting were the narrow-minded comments of the article. <br /><br />I felt that the main point of the article is that just because it's charity, it doesn't make it any less of SWEDOW (Stuff We Don't Want). Quite frankly, SWEDOW for us may just be SWEDOW for them as well.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2011/10/11/haiti_doesnt_need_your_old_tshirt">Another Foreign Policy article</a> discusses this a little further, but I think there is a serious disconnect in people's minds over what we THINK they need and what they do. One commenter sarcastically says that she's learned that "it would be better for a child to remain shirtless than to have [donated shirts]." But that seems to suggest that this person honestly feels that children (and adults alike?) would be running around naked in impoverished countries were it not for kindly donations of shirts commemorating failed Super Bowl bids.<br /><br />Another commenter, one that seems to have become the "alpha commenter," asks if it's better then to go without new shoes, new clothes or no bed instead of a yoga mat. But that's&nbsp; a straw man argument -- it implies that it's either these things or nothing. And I seriously doubt if that's true.<br /><br />The way I read the article, I think the message is that it would be better to instead support developing a local industry instead of bringing in outside goods. The same applies to the US, right? I mean, people all around bemoan cheap Chinese goods being dumped on the market, and rally behind "Buy American!" Why can't the same thing apply to countries or areas in need? Sure, I agree -- some teddy bears would cheer kids up. But instead of donating "gently used items," as one commenter suggests (and seriously, from personal experience, I think we all know that the definition of "gently used" varies from person to person), donate cash wisely (as another commenter suggests) to outfits that will help support local industry and development. Forget donating shoes -- donate to an outfit that will train people to make shoes. If in Tibet there's only cheap Chinese parkas available, donate to outfits that will help train locals to make their own parkas out of local materials. <br /><br />Sure, those outfits may not always exist. But by NOT donating to outfits that send used panties to third world countries, and by getting involved with responsible outfits, maybe you can help create new, more helpful ventures.<br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Cherry blossoms blossoming earlier</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/03/cherry-blossoms-blossoming-earlier.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.525</id>

    <published>2012-03-15T07:24:35Z</published>
    <updated>2012-03-15T07:29:25Z</updated>

    <summary>Think Progress has an interesting article on blossoming trends for Japanese cherry trees in D.C., showing a clear trend in earlier blossoming since 1921. As we slowly start to enter the cherry blossom season here in Japan, I&apos;ll poke around...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="cherryblossoms" label="cherry blossoms" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="climate" label="climate" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="globalwarming" label="global warming" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="japan" label="Japan" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[Think Progress has an interesting article on <a href="http://thinkprogress.org/green/2012/03/13/443449/as-climate-changes-tidal-basin-cherry-blossoms-could-peak-at-their-earliest-yet/">blossoming trends for Japanese cherry trees</a> in D.C., showing a clear trend in earlier blossoming since 1921. <br /><br />As we slowly start to enter the cherry blossom season here in Japan, I'll poke around and see if I can find anything showing trends for Japanese cherries. I remember living in Himeji and seeing trees blossom after one particularly hot early March week.<br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>My dream vacation...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kirkandersen.net/2012/03/my-dream-vacation.html" />
    <id>tag:kirkandersen.net,2012://12.524</id>

    <published>2012-03-15T07:20:53Z</published>
    <updated>2012-03-15T07:23:09Z</updated>

    <summary>It&apos;s always been my dream to go to Greenland, and here&apos;s an outfit managing tours! Check &apos;em out. Best of all, the dates line up perfectly with my Obon holiday period, so I wouldn&apos;t really have to miss much work....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kirk</name>
        <uri>http://kirkandersen.net</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="greenland" label="Greenland" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="vacation" label="vacation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kirkandersen.net/">
        <![CDATA[It's always been my dream to go to Greenland, and <a href="http://www.scantours.net/products/qaqortog-man-stone/963/">here's an outfit managing tours</a>! Check 'em out. Best of all, the dates line up perfectly with my Obon holiday period, so I wouldn't really have to miss much work. <br /><br />Best get going before all the ice melts, I suppose...<br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

</feed>
